qples.com 2013-04-14

# Privacy Policy

##### **Updated: July 2012**

##### **Qples, Inc. (Qples) and your Privacy**

This privacy statement covers the site [www.Qples.com](http://www.qples.com/) and its related websites, services, software applications and products (“Sites”), as well as our clients, advertisers and affiliates (collectively, “Affiliates”). Qples is committed to our users' privacy.  This Privacy Policy is intended to help you understand what personal and non-personal information we collect, how it is protected and used, and how you can control it.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact privacy (at) Qples.com.  Changes to this Privacy Policy will be made on this web page, with an updated “Updated” date, above.

At Qples we respect your right to privacy and we understand that, as a visitor to our website, you prefer to control your own personal information preferences. For this reason, we may ask you to register or provide personal information and preferences when you visit certain areas of our website. Here are some examples of when Qples may ask for / collect personal information – when you:

  * View, print, or otherwise interact with coupons
  * Redeem coupons
  * Register with Qples or its Affiliates
  * Facebook Connect or similar external registration methods
  * Chat or communicate with customer service
  * Request information
  * Download Qples software, applications, mobile applications, etc.
  * Register for events
  * Register for products / new products, programs or promotions
  * Purchase Products or Services
  * Subscribe to newsletters
  * Share our service or offers, etc., with your friends
  * Interact with some ads or offers
  * Register or interact with us via Facebook Connect or other social media provider.

Note:  Using Qples software or applications, including mobile applications, may require the collection of information about the device in order to detect and prevent coupon or other fraud.  This may include the installation of a device identifier that may remain in-place, even if the software or application(s) are removed.  This is used to prevent fraud, and does not include personal information.

Our Sites may contain links to third-party websites, products and services.  This Privacy Policy only applies to our Sites and our collection and use of your information. The linked third party websites, products and services, and their collection and use of your information, are governed by the privacy policies of such third parties. We encourage you to learn about the privacy practices of those third parties.

We will guard the personal information you share with us to ensure the content and services we provide on our website are always tailored to your current, designated preferences. Your privacy is extremely important to us, and your information is kept strictly confidential and will never be given to anyone outside our company.

Qples respects the rights users give us when opting to receive e-mail or other forms of communication and enforces internal policies to preserve those rights. It is our objective to retain the long-term ability to continue to communicate with our customers and interested parties.

If you do not want Qples or Qples representatives to contact you, you may "opt-out" of this preference at any time, whether you're online or contacting Qples directly. As an option, you'll always have the flexibility to opt back in at anytime based on previous information or newly updated information.

##### **Collecting personal information**

When you browse our websites, you are able to do so anonymously. Generally, we don't collect personal information when you browse, not even your email address. Your browser, however, does automatically tell us the type of computer and operating system you are using.

Like most standard Web site servers our website uses log files and cookies. A "cookie"  is a small line of text that is stored with your web browser for record-keeping purposes and helps Qples provide better service to you. Your browser has an option to accept, reject, or provide you with notice when a cookie is sent.

Once a user enters our websites, a cookie follows them through their click stream path collecting information including internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use only. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information.

When you use a Qples site or application, certain technologies may be used to collect non-personal information.  Technologies used may include but are not limited to web beacons and cookies, IP addresses, unique device IDs, user IDs, and log files.  These activities can include:

  * Coupon requests
  * Coupon prints
  * Coupon redemptions
  * Web browser type and/or operating system and/or platform
  * Referral website
  * Pages viewed
  * Ads viewed and interacted with
  * Access dates and times
  * Geo location

##### **Location Information** :

Use of the Sites, including mobile applications, may include location-based services. If you use those services, Qples may receive information about your location which Qples may use to send you geographically relevant promotions or advertisements.

##### **Analytic Tools** :

Qples may use tools such as Google Analytics to better understand who is using our Sites and how they are using them. These tools use cookies to collect information such as time of visit, pages visited, time spent on each page of the website, IP address, and type of operating system used. Qples may use the data collected from visitor cookies in aggregate form only and does not tie to them any personally identifiable information. Use of this information helps Qples better understand what users are seeking and learning on Qples websites and helps Qples identify potential navigation issues.

##### **Promotions, Sweepstakes, & Contests**:

From time to time, Qples may sponsor sweepstakes, contests, other promotions or surveys. Personal information may be required as a condition of participation for purposes of fraud prevention and verifying entrants' identities, notifying winners and fulfilling prizes. Qples will not use or disclose any such information unless Qples receives your consent to do so. If Qples engage a third party to assist us in administering a promotion or fulfilling prizes, this information will be disclosed to that third party.

##### **Data Retention** :

Qples retain all information collected about you for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

Here are some examples of how we use the information we collect:

  * To operate our service, including the offering, delivery and redemption of coupons and other services and products
  * To operate our offers and advertisements and promotions and similar activities
  * Measure and adjust the effectiveness of offers and campaigns
  * Collect information so we can analyze it and improve our service by understanding trends and preferences and other measures and metrics
  * Improve the look and feel of our Sites
  * Assist you (users) in the operation of the Sites and services
  * Create new products, functions and features
  * To facilitate customer service and improvements in customer service
  * To help make the offers and advertisements and products we present to you to be more timely and relevant

##### **How we protect your personal information:**

Qples will always protect the personal information that you share with us. Qples stores information internally in a controlled, secure environment.

We do not share personally identifiable information with our Affiliates or other third-parties for their marketing or promotional uses except as part of a specific program or feature that you have actively chosen to participate in.

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering purchases, sending postal mail and processing event registration. We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

If Qples requests general demographic information, this information is limited to reporting purposes only; users remain anonymous. Phone numbers, e-mail addresses, and postal addresses are never shared for demographic reports with outside entities.

The Sites incorporate physical, electronic, and administrative procedures to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information. Additional security measures, such as Secure Sockets Layer (“SSL”) or other technology, will be used if you engage in financial transactions on our Sites. However, as no security measures are perfect or impenetrable, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us.

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our website, or as required by law.

##### **Our Commitment To Children’s Privacy**

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, we do not knowingly collect or maintain information from persons under 13 years of age, and no part of our Sites is structured to attract anyone under 13. If you are under 13 years of age, then please do not use or access the Sites at any time or in any manner. If we learn that personally identifiable information of persons under 13 years of age has been collected on the Sites without verified parental consent, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information.

##### **How to update your personal information:**

You can help Qples maintain the accuracy of your personal information by notifying us when you change your name, address, title, phone number, e-mail address, or your content preferences. If at any time you wish to update your information or preferences, or you prefer to stop receiving communication from Qples, feel free to contact us at any time.

Qples Privacy Contacts

E-MAIL: [privacy@Qples.com](mailto:privacy@Qples.com)  
POSTAL MAIL:  
Qples, INC..  
Attn: Privacy  
5930 Royal Lane, Suite 381  
Dallas, TX  75230

If you change your e-mail or postal address, please contact Qples. In order to make the appropriate corrections, please include both your old and new address.

##### **Our company wide commitment to privacy: **

To make sure your personal information remains confidential, we communicate these privacy guidelines to every Qples employee.

##### **Links:**

Our websites may contain links to other websites. Qples assumes no responsibility for the content or the privacy policies and practices of such websites. Qples encourages you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites; their privacy practices may differ from ours.

##### **Notification of Changes:**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

##### **Business Transitions:**

In the event Qples goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users'; personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via a prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section.
